<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<DocEntity xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" Name="IfcOpticalMaterialProperties" UniqueId="1kcfl83A9BRPNbpP2HJ8Lf" DiagramNumber="3" BaseDefinition="IfcMaterialProperties" EntityFlags="237">
	<Attributes>
		<DocAttribute Name="VisibleTransmittance" UniqueId="3ED_y4BNfCUhfyKOqdrkbE" DefinedType="IfcPositiveRatioMeasure" AttributeFlags="1" AggregationType="0" AggregationFlag="0">
			<Documentation>Transmittance at normal incidence (visible). Defines the fraction of the visible spectrum of solar radiation that passes through per unit area, perpendicular to the surface.</Documentation>
		</DocAttribute>
		<DocAttribute Name="SolarTransmittance" UniqueId="3oEPXrnMX269mN$Id5t0ea" DefinedType="IfcPositiveRatioMeasure" AttributeFlags="1" AggregationType="0" AggregationFlag="0">
			<Documentation>Transmittance at normal incidence (solar). Defines the fraction of solar radiation that passes through per unit area, perpendicular to the surface.</Documentation>
		</DocAttribute>
		<DocAttribute Name="ThermalIrTransmittance" UniqueId="3a6HoWVgf9QgqoGZnDzRuN" DefinedType="IfcPositiveRatioMeasure" AttributeFlags="1" AggregationType="0" AggregationFlag="0">
			<Documentation>Thermal IR transmittance at normal incidence. Defines the fraction of thermal energy that passes through per unit area, perpendicular to the surface.</Documentation>
		</DocAttribute>
		<DocAttribute Name="ThermalIrEmissivityBack" UniqueId="076jdRQKP8OhKKt2EhP0In" DefinedType="IfcPositiveRatioMeasure" AttributeFlags="1" AggregationType="0" AggregationFlag="0">
			<Documentation>Thermal IR emissivity: back side. Defines the fraction of thermal energy emitted per unit area to &quot;blackbody&quot; at the same temperature, through the &quot;back&quot; side of the material.</Documentation>
		</DocAttribute>
		<DocAttribute Name="ThermalIrEmissivityFront" UniqueId="1JyLN1cxfA9OMbGcoaFrmu" DefinedType="IfcPositiveRatioMeasure" AttributeFlags="1" AggregationType="0" AggregationFlag="0">
			<Documentation>Thermal IR emissivity: front side. Defines the fraction of thermal energy emitted per unit area to &quot;blackbody&quot; at the same temperature, through the &quot;front&quot; side of the material.</Documentation>
		</DocAttribute>
		<DocAttribute Name="VisibleReflectanceBack" UniqueId="3qA7Ub_lnDjBIGNTpKyl$I" DefinedType="IfcPositiveRatioMeasure" AttributeFlags="1" AggregationType="0" AggregationFlag="0">
			<Documentation>Reflectance at normal incidence (visible): back side. Defines the fraction of the solar ray in the visible spectrum that is reflected and not transmitted when the ray passes from one medium
into another, at the &quot;back&quot; side of the other material, perpendicular to the surface. Dependent on material and surface characteristics.</Documentation>
		</DocAttribute>
		<DocAttribute Name="VisibleReflectanceFront" UniqueId="1SLEFv2HXBj94RGNYSqy11" DefinedType="IfcPositiveRatioMeasure" AttributeFlags="1" AggregationType="0" AggregationFlag="0">
			<Documentation>Reflectance at normal incidence (visible): front side. Defines the fraction of the solar ray in the visible spectrum that is reflected and not transmitted when the ray passes from one medium
into another, at the &quot;front&quot; side of the other material, perpendicular to the surface. Dependent on material and surface characteristics.</Documentation>
		</DocAttribute>
		<DocAttribute Name="SolarReflectanceFront" UniqueId="3H5xLpmDL0rvnyW6fEZdXQ" DefinedType="IfcPositiveRatioMeasure" AttributeFlags="1" AggregationType="0" AggregationFlag="0">
			<Documentation>Reflectance at normal incidence (solar): front side. Defines the fraction of the solar ray that is reflected and not transmitted when the ray passes from one medium into another, at the &quot;front&quot; side of the other material, perpendicular to the surface. Dependent on material and surface characteristics.</Documentation>
		</DocAttribute>
		<DocAttribute Name="SolarReflectanceBack" UniqueId="0jqrJbwkH1z8IccFEwXOlY" DefinedType="IfcPositiveRatioMeasure" AttributeFlags="1" AggregationType="0" AggregationFlag="0">
			<Documentation>Reflectance at normal incidence (solar): back side. Defines the fraction of the solar ray that is reflected and not transmitted when the ray passes from one medium into another, at the &quot;back&quot; side of the other material, perpendicular to the surface. Dependent on material and surface characteristics.</Documentation>
		</DocAttribute>
	</Attributes>
	<UniqueRules>
		<DocUniqueRule Name="UR11" UniqueId="1vfQOXeqb3Res6C0Lohtm7">
			<Items>
				<DocUniqueRuleItem Name="Material" UniqueId="0PYBpYCQ579u7Ylgvn4fjm" />
			</Items>
		</DocUniqueRule>
	</UniqueRules>
</DocEntity>

