<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<DocEntity xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" Name="IfcStructuralActivity" UniqueId="367339a3-2c53-452e-880f-d16b0575c0c3" BaseDefinition="IfcProduct" EntityFlags="141">
	<Localization>
		<DocLocalization Locale="de" Name="Einwirkungen / Reaktionen des Tragwerks" />
		<DocLocalization Locale="en" Name="Structural Activity" />
		<DocLocalization Locale="fr" Name="Activité structurelle" />
	</Localization>
	<Subtypes>
		<DocSubtype UniqueId="ed6dec8f-c417-4aee-93ac-88d568889bee" DefinedType="IfcStructuralAction" />
		<DocSubtype UniqueId="4a849529-1603-4d99-b9e9-015bf87ff19b" DefinedType="IfcStructuralReaction" />
	</Subtypes>
	<Attributes>
		<DocAttribute Name="AppliedLoad" UniqueId="8a68177b-4c60-4eb6-8903-ae9366cb2ac7" DefinedType="IfcStructuralLoad" XsdFormat="attribute">
			<Documentation>Load or result resource object which defines the load type, direction, and load values.

In case of activities which are variably distributed over curves or surfaces, _IfcStructuralLoadConfiguration_ is used which provides a list of load samples and their locations within the load distribution, measured in local coordinates of the curve or surface on which this activity acts. The contents of this load or result distribution may be further restricted by definitions at subtypes of _IfcStructuralActivity_.</Documentation>
		</DocAttribute>
		<DocAttribute Name="GlobalOrLocal" UniqueId="830a06f0-c7f3-4922-adc8-1ae743e63028" DefinedType="IfcGlobalOrLocalEnum">
			<Documentation>Indicates whether the load directions refer to the global coordinate system (global to
the analysis model, i.e. as established by _IfcStructuralAnalysisModel.SharedPlacement_)
or to the local coordinate system (local to the activity or connected item, as established by
an explicit or implied representation and its parameter space).

&gt; NOTE, the informal definition of _IfcRepresentationResource.IfcGlobalOrLocalEnum_ doe s not distinguish between &quot;global coordinate system&quot; and &quot;world coordinate system&quot;. On the other hand, this distinction is necessary in the _IfcStructuralAnalysisDomain_ where the shared &quot;global&quot; coordinate system of an analysis model may very well not be the same as the project-wide world coordinate system.

&gt; NOTE&amp;nbsp; In the scope of _IfcStructuralActivity.GlobalOrLocal_, the meaning of GLOBAL_COORDS is therefore not to be taken as world coordinate system but as the analysis model specific shared coordinate system. In contrast, LOCAL_COORDS is to be taken as coordinates which are local to individual structural items and activities, as established by subclass-specific geometry use definitions.</Documentation>
		</DocAttribute>
		<DocAttribute Name="AssignedToStructuralItem" UniqueId="972e6dd1-44d3-4eae-8b18-92babea8b77f" DefinedType="IfcRelConnectsStructuralActivity" AttributeFlags="8" AggregationType="3" AggregationLower="0" AggregationUpper="1" Inverse="RelatedStructuralActivity">
			<Documentation>Reference to the _IfcRelConnectsStructuralActivity_ relationship by which activities are connected with structural items.</Documentation>
		</DocAttribute>
	</Attributes>
</DocEntity>

