<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<DocEntity xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" Name="IfcStructuralLoadTemperature" UniqueId="a5520d12-ec69-4ee1-85ae-cce5fdfdec16" BaseDefinition="IfcStructuralLoadStatic" EntityFlags="237">
	<Localization>
		<DocLocalization Locale="de" Name="Temperaturlast" />
		<DocLocalization Locale="en" Name="Structural Load Temperature" />
	</Localization>
	<Attributes>
		<DocAttribute Name="DeltaTConstant" UniqueId="8eed99bf-afb7-4901-987c-79c8f2db4a8f" DefinedType="IfcThermodynamicTemperatureMeasure" AttributeFlags="1">
			<Documentation>Temperature change which affects the complete section of the structural member, or the uniform portion of a non-uniform temperature change.

&gt; NOTE&amp;nbsp; A positive value describes an increase in temperature. I.e. a positive constant temperature change causes elongation of a member, or compression in the member if there are respective restraints.</Documentation>
		</DocAttribute>
		<DocAttribute Name="DeltaTY" UniqueId="88453b8b-b391-4621-9721-0560f4706228" DefinedType="IfcThermodynamicTemperatureMeasure" AttributeFlags="1">
			<Documentation>Non-uniform temperature change, specified as the difference of the temperature change at the outer fibre of the positive y direction minus the temperature change at the outer fibre of the negative y direction of the analysis member.

&gt; NOTE&amp;nbsp; A positive non-uniform temperature change in y induces a negative curvature of the member about z, or a positive bending moment about z if there are respective restraints. y and z are local member axes.</Documentation>
		</DocAttribute>
		<DocAttribute Name="DeltaTZ" UniqueId="80c8cbce-08ae-4f55-a98f-2ca70bbc7dd6" DefinedType="IfcThermodynamicTemperatureMeasure" AttributeFlags="1">
			<Documentation>Non-uniform temperature change, specified as the difference of the temperature change at the outer fibre of the positive z direction minus the temperature change at the outer fibre of the negative z direction of the analysis member.

&gt; NOTE&amp;nbsp; A positive non-uniform temperature change in z induces a positive curvature of the member about y, or a negative bending moment about y if there are respective restraints. y and z are local member axes.</Documentation>
		</DocAttribute>
	</Attributes>
</DocEntity>

